# Paul Ramsey Swift

256 Belfast Dr · Charleston, SC 29407 · (478) 919.0100 · paulrswift@yahoo.com

Highly motivated associate experienced in managing complex projects in front end web development, customer service, human resources, and sales. Excels in fast-paced, deadline-driven environments. Detailed self-starter able to multi-task projects simultaneously. Offering core competencies in:

**JavaScript** 

HTML

Backbone

**CSS** 

Project Management Account Management Salesforce

**Oral Presentations** 

inContact

Cisco Desk Agent

HIPPA Compliance

Microsoft Office

## **Career Experiences**

## **Benefitfocus**

September 2013 - September 2016

**Configuration Consultant** 

- Worked within strict SLAs to renew insurance carrier plans
- Worked in team setting to find alternative solutions to define boundaries of the problem/request Team Lead, Benefit Support Center
  - Interpreted business requirements from customers into written specifications
  - Performed regular training sessions of software and software support techniques
  - Delivered and produced monthly reports for internal stakeholders
  - Participated in weekly client conference calls, distributes takeaways to team members

Benefit Administrator, Approvals Specialist

- Approved qualified life events within Benefitfocus software by verifying documentation
- Produced daily task report to be provided to client

**Application Consultant** 

- Carrier, Administration, and Member IT support/website navigational assistance
- Initial point of contact; 90% first pass resolution, 60+ calls daily

## The Blood Alliance

September 2011 - August 2013

Account Manager

- Liaison between clients and staff to schedule and execute cost effective use of resources
- Oral presentations and public relation events to civic and business associations
- Delivered remote and onsite training sessions of software

### State Farm, Jeff Cain Agency

January 2011 - September 2011

Insurance Sales Specialist

- Provided a high level of product knowledge to best service policy holders
- Primary contact for policy holders. Responded in a timely, friendly and efficient manner

#### **Easterlin Pecan Co and Pearson Farm**

July 2010 - January 2011

Logistics Management/Purchasing Agent

- Supervised loading of shipments; 5-7 per day
- Produced daily inventories, productions and shipping manifests

#### Wonderland Co LTD.

February 2009 - March 2010

Instructor. Deagu, South Korea

- Taught English to 35+ Korean students/supplemented English to 11 Korean Instructors
- Assisted fellow team members to meet weekly curriculum and reporting deadlines

Education

Front End Engineering The Iron Yard, Charleston, SC

#### Bachelors of Business Administration

Georgia College and State University, Milledgeville, Georgia